Hongyi He Chinese papercuts collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Hongyi He Chinese papercuts collection 1989-2007
AFC 2006/008
Hongyi He
approximately 365 items
4 containers
0.4 linear feet
manuscripts 350 items
8 photographs: digital, black and white, color (JPEG, TIF)
2 framed cut-paper works: paper; various sizes.
5 videocassettes of 5 (Mini-DV) (3 hours 30 min.): digital, color, sound.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The collection documents Hongyi He's method and philosophy behind her papercutting repertory through her biography, publications, and samples of her work. Papercuts created during a lecture/demonstration and interview at the Library of Congress on February 24, 2006, are also contained in this collection, along with several paper-cuts that were later donated to the American Folklife Center.
Provenance
Hongyi He; Donation; 2006, 2007
Access and Restrictions
The Hongyi He Chinese papercuts collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Hongyi He is a Chinese papercut artist recognized as a "master of folk arts and crafts" by UNESCO. She was born in Wuhan, Hubei, China, on May 1, 1954. Her father was a professor of philosophy and her mother was an amateur embroider and Chinese traditional painter. Her maternal grandmother was a renowned folk storyteller. Hongyi He started paper cutting as a hobby when she was twelve years old, and kept this particular hobby throughout China's turbulent historical transformation. She earned a bachelor's and master's degrees in folk literature and arts from Common University of Central China, in 1980 and 1982 respectively. After her graduation, she began teaching at National South-Central China University in Wuhan. While working, she was sent to Beijing Normal University for a half year as part of a training program for faculty of folklore and folk art. At this program, she met her mentor and teacher, Zhong-Jin Wen, a leading scholar of Chinese folk art. He influenced her work and encouraged her to create contemporary folk art as a papercut artist. Hongyi He has attended conferences, given lectures, and presented exhibitions in China, Korea, Japan, and the United States. At the "Fourth World Conference on Women" held in Beijing in 1995, Hongyi He presented her papercut, "The Wedding of the Rats," which was a collaboration between three generations including her mother and daughter. She owns over 1,000 papercuts made by other artists, as well as pieces of her own work. She currently teaches at the National South-Central China University in Wuhan. She is also an active artist in the United States and promotes her art among Chinese communities in metropolitan Washington, DC, through lectures and workshops.
Scope and Content
The collection documents Hongyi He’s method and philosophy behind her papercutting repertory through her biography, publications, and samples of her work. Papercuts created during a lecture/demonstration and interview at the Library of Congress on February 24, 2006, are also contained in this collection, along with several artifacts that were later donated to the American Folklife Center. While the collection is predominantly in English, the lecture/demonstration is in Chinese and English. Some publications are in Chinese varying between traditional and simplified Chinese.
The majority of the papercuts and publications illustrate He's in-depth interest in Chinese folk literature and Chinese ethnic groups. There are 27 small papercuts of animal characters and baby characters that are especially popular among Chinese living in rural areas. For many, these pieces represent Chinese culture and custom, wealth, and prosperity. There are also 15 small paper cuts of pandas made especially for children.
Oversize materials in the collection include: the Library of Congress' Asian Pacific American Heritage Month poster showing one of He’s paper cut pieces which was created during the lecture/demonstration; two papercuts of women’s hair decorations, one of the Miao people of Guizhou (blue), and the other of Tibetan origin (red); and twelve Chinese zodiac animals (mouse, ox, tiger, rabbit, dragon, snake, horse, sheep, monkey, rooster, dog, pig). Each zodiac animal papercut is red and each animal character is contained within a blue papercut background. According to the artist, these zodiac pieces are window decorations for Chinese New Year. The hair decoration and zodiac pieces were cut from a special type of paper that can be ironed, and the artist used special scissors to cut the delicate shapes of certain parts.
Arrangement
The Hongyi He Chinese papercuts collection is arranged into the following series: 1. Lecture-related materials; 2. Published materials; 3. Graphic materials; 4. Interview of Hongyi He; Series 5. Papercuts series.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
He, Hongyi; He, Hongyi--Interviews.; Yeh, Nora
Organizations
American Folklife Center
Subjects
Cut-out craft--China.; Folk art--China.; Folk artists--China--Interviews.; Paper work--China.
Places
Washington (D.C.), event place.
Form/Genre
Computer files.; Cut-paper work.; Digital photographs.; Digital recordings.; Digital video.; Interviews.; Video recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Lecture-related materials
  - Printout of Powerpoint used in lecture presentation, February 6, 2006 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Lecture notes, February 6, 2006 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Printout of flyer for lecture, February 6, 2006 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Library of Congress Gazette, January 27, 2006 (Box-folder 1/4)
    Article about the lecture in the newspaper Mei Hua, December 20, 2007.
  - Asian Pacific American Heritage Month, keynote program, May 4, 2006 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Flyer for Library of Congress lecture and demonstration by Wenzhang Wang and Hongyi He, April 2007 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Series 2: Published materials
  - Biography of Hongyi He, from Folklore Studies, 1989 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Zao Zhi Shu, paper-cut instruction book written by Hongyi He (Box-folder 1/8)
  - "A Handful of Seeds: Papercut Workshop in the 1930s," Christian Art Information (November 2001). (Box-folder 1/9)
  - "Scissors," China’s Ethnic Groups, 30/2 (June 2005). (Box-folder 1/10)
- Series 3: Graphic materials
  - Graphic materials-printouts from CF01 (Box-folder 1/11)
    Black-and-white printouts of color digital images (original images on AFC 2006/008: CF01) with captions.
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: PH01- PH06, February 2006
    Images depict Pam Johnson, Nora Yeh, Tsai Hong Miller, Hongyi He, Rata Sun Lewi, and Peggy Bulger at the American Folklife Center and Jefferson Building recording studio, February 2006.
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: PH07
    Banner printout from document "About Rats."
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: PH08- PH10
    Black-and-white printouts of digital images of papercuts (original images on AFC 2006/008: CF03) with explanations.
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: PH11- PH15
    Black-and-white printouts digital papercut printouts from document "Chinese Folksongs" (original images on AFC 2006/008: CF01).
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: CF01
    Zip disk of color digital images.
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: CF02, February 24, 2006
    CD containing PowerPoint presentation of Hongyi He's demonstration/lecture.
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: CF03
    Color digital files of photographs of Hongyi He’s papercut collection. Five pictures entitled "Folksong," 3 pictures entitled "Bird," 2 pictures entitled "Rats."
- Series 4: Moving images
  - Hongyi He interview conducted by Nora Yeh at the Library of Congress Recording Laboratory, February 24, 2006, AFC 2006/008: MV01-MV04
    Consists of three sections: 1. History of Chinese papercuts; 2. Characteristics (technique, materials, usages) of Chinese papercuts; 3. Hongyi He’s work and life story. The entire interview is in Chinese with English translations by Nora Yeh in each section. Approximately 3 hours and 30 minutes.
- Series 5: Papercuts
  - Papercuts (AFC 2006/008: AR01-AR45) (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: AR01 - AR 03, 3 3.5 x 5 in. papercuts
    White rabbit papercuts.
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: AR04 - AR 06, 3 3 x 3.5 in. papercuts
    Dog papercuts in red, yellow, and black.
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: AR07 - AR 08, 2 4 x 3.5 in. papercuts
    Dog papercuts in red and green.
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: AR09 - AR 10, 2 3.5 x 4 in.; 1 4 x 4.5 in. papercuts
    A girl and a boy.
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: AR11, 1 7 x 7 in. papercut
    A circular green butterfly papercut used in the demonstration.
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: AR12, 1 8.5 x 8.5 in. papercut
    A red baby papercut.
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: AR13 - AR27, 15 2.25 x 2.5 in. papercuts
    Papercuts of black bear in a white background.
  - Papercuts and prints of papercuts mostly by Hongyi-He (Box-folder 1/13)
    Some of the papercuts and prints are unidentified.
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: AR28, 1 11 x 16 in. papercut (Box-folder 2/1)
    Hongyi He's papercut used for a Library of Congress poster.
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: AR29, 1 20 x 21 in. papercut
    Light purple flower papercut that was used for demonstration in the lecture.
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: AR30 - AR31, 2 12 x 16 in. papercuts
    Tibetan and Miao women head decoration papercuts, red and blue respectively.
  - Chinese zodiac animal papercuts (Box-folder 2/2)
    Includes five zodiac animals.
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: AR32 - AR36, 5 17.5 x 17.5 in. papercuts
    Papercuts of an ox, a tiger, a rabbit, a rat, and a snake. Each animal is made in red paper and located in the middle of each paper cut. The edges of each papercut have various decorations in dark blue.
  - Item IDs: AFC 2006/008: AR37 - AR43 (Box-folder 2/3)
    Papercuts of a dragon, a horse, a goat, a monkey, a dog, a rooster and a pig.
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: AR44, 1 11 x 14 in. papercut (Box 3)
    Framed and autographed papercut of a dragon in red paper, by Hongyi He.
  - Item ID: AFC 2006/008: AR45, 1 11 x 14 in. papercut (Box 4)
    Framed and autographed papercut of a phoenix in red paper, by Hongyi He.